<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TrueBlocks on</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in TrueBlocks on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:47:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>/docs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/</guid><description>Are you here for the OpenData Community Hackathon?
Install the docker version and download (or build) the Unchained Index Tutorials: Showing ERC20 transfers on the token contract Listing contracts created by an address (including UniSwap) Monthly ERC20 token balance for one or more addresses Calling into smart contracts with chifra state The Rent is Too Damn High Commanding the Line &amp;#8593
Are blockchains really meeting their promise?
Problem Statement If you&amp;rsquo;re like us, you fell in love with blockchains because of the promise they provide: world-wide, private, and permissionless access to the most accurate and agreed-upon data ever produced.</description></item><item><title>TrueBlocks Papers</title><link>/papers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 13:06:08 -0300</pubDate><guid>/papers/</guid><description>2023
Unchained Index Spec v0.51.0-beta 2022
Unchained Index File Format Spec (v0.40.0-beta - deprecated) 2021
The Difference Between TrueBlocks and theGraph 2020
Index Chunk File Format (deprecated) Bloom Filter File Format (deprecated) 2018
Decentralized, Off-Chain, per-Block Accounting, Monitoring, and Reconciliation for Blockchains Enhanced Adaptive Bloom Filters for Identifying Transactions of Interest Faster, Richer, Fully Customizable Data from Programmable Blockchains</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>/blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Data model</title><link>/data-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/</guid><description>Reference pages about working with Ethereum and TrueBlocks-collected data. Jump to the data model introduction</description></item><item><title>Chifra Command Line</title><link>/chifra/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/</guid><description>The chifra command provides access to all the applications and tools available:
Purpose: Access to all TrueBlocks tools (chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help for more). Accounts: list list every appearance of an address anywhere on the chain export export full detail of transactions for one or more addresses monitors add, remove, clean, and list address monitors names query addresses or names of well known accounts abis fetches the ABI for a smart contract Chain Data: blocks retrieve one or more blocks from the chain or local cache transactions retrieve one or more transactions from the chain or local cache receipts retrieve receipts for the given transaction(s) logs retrieve logs for the given transaction(s) traces retrieve traces for the given transaction(s) when find block(s) based on date, blockNum, timestamp, or 'special' Chain State: state retrieve account balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) tokens retrieve token balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) Admin: status report on the status of the TrueBlocks system serve serve the TrueBlocks API using the flame server scrape scan the chain and update (and optionally pin) the TrueBlocks index of appearances chunks manage and investigate chunks and bloom filters init initialize the TrueBlocks system by downloading from IPFS Other: quotes update or display Ethereum price data, this tool has been deprecated explore open a local or remote explorer for one or more addresses, blocks, or transactions slurp fetch data from EtherScan for any address Flags: -h, --help display this help screen Use &amp;quot;chifra [command] --help&amp;quot; for more information about a command.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>/contact/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:25:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>/contact/</guid><description>The best way to contact us is through Discord, but if you must send us a note at info at quickblocks dot io.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Policy</title><link>/privacy-policy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 19:23:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>/privacy-policy/</guid><description>TrueBlocks doesn&amp;rsquo;t track anything!!</description></item><item><title>Dockers</title><link>/docker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docker/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Explorers</title><link>/explorer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/explorer/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Sdks</title><link>/sdks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/sdks/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>