<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trueblocks on</title><link>/tags/trueblocks/</link><description>Recent content in trueblocks on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:28 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/trueblocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Better Token Accounting</title><link>/blog/better-token-accounting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/better-token-accounting/</guid><description>Eth accounting is identical Token accounting is improved in these ways:
Intra block token accounting Account for every Transfer event If a balance is incorrect, do one of three things: If the transaction contains a &amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; input, and the event says something transferred, but the balances don&amp;rsquo;t change, lable probably-spam and add a field called removal of phony transfer in If the function is one of a very small number of common mint functions, assign to knownMint field If the function is one of a very small number of common burn methods, assign to a knownBurn field If the balance goes up - label the transation as implied-mint and add to a feild called impliedMint If the balance goes down - label the reconciliation as impied-burn and add to a field called impliedBurn Bugs fixed: In previous code, if a token transacted multple times in a single block the entire net transfer was assigned to the first transfer.</description></item><item><title>forEveryChain</title><link>/blog/foreverychain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/foreverychain/</guid><description>Have you ever had the desire to look at every trace of every transaction of every block on every blockchain? Yes? Well, pull up a chair and visit with us for a while.
It’s a Multi-Chain World I’m sure many of you are aware of the coming &amp;ldquo;multi-chain&amp;rdquo; universe of blockchains. You know the one. The one where all sorts of little baby communities of people are going to be doing all sorts of little baby community-like things.</description></item><item><title>Other articles published in 2021</title><link>/blog/other-articles-published-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/other-articles-published-in-2021/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s links to a few other articles we published in 2021 on Medium.
The Rent is Too Damn High The Rent is Too Damn High - Part II Adventures in Difficulty Bombing Calling Smart Contracts with chifra state --call Commanding the Line Compacting ERC20 Logs</description></item><item><title>A Long Winded Explanation of TrueBlocks</title><link>/blog/a-long-winded-explanation-of-trueblocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 19:21:58 -0300</pubDate><guid>/blog/a-long-winded-explanation-of-trueblocks/</guid><description>Recently, I was engaged in a tweetstorm with Nick Johnson, for whom I have deep, deep respect. The storm was about the topic of indexing the Ethereum blockchain. As is usually the case with my tweetstorms, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I explained myself well during the thunder and lightning, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d take a moment during the lull to better explain myself. So this is an explanation for Nick (and anyone else who&amp;rsquo;s listening) about how TrueBlocks indexes the Ethereum blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Traversers for TrueBlocks</title><link>/blog/dynamic-traversers-for-trueblocks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 12:29:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/dynamic-traversers-for-trueblocks/</guid><description>Dynamic Traversers in TrueBlocks Ethereum nodes come to consensus on a world-wide global ledger of smart contract invocations every 14 seconds. Everyone know this. This is what we celebrate about the chain. Not only is this data world-wide and consented-to, but it is also permissionless. At least that’s what we’re supposed to believe.
But, is it really permissionless?
I think the answer to that question is a resounding “No.” Ask yourself how you personally get data from the Ethereum blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Building Your Own Ethereum Archive Node</title><link>/blog/building-your-own-ethereum-archive-node/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 18:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/building-your-own-ethereum-archive-node/</guid><description>This article is incomplete in the extreme.
[Jan 20, 2021: Since writing this article, we’ve come upon a project called TurboGeth. It reduces the size of the hard drive needed for an archive node from 6TB to around 1.5TB. Significant difference. Same data. Less costs.]
In the first part, we simply present pictures and prices for the components we used to build the two Ethereum archive nodes we run in house.</description></item><item><title>How Accurate is EtherScan?</title><link>/blog/how-accurate-is-etherscan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 03:59:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/how-accurate-is-etherscan/</guid><description>Why build an 18-decimal place accurate ledger if it doesn’t balance?
[Accompanying Video]
I had a call this morning with a cryptocurrency accountant. He’s a wonderful fellow. One of those people who can happily wade through thousands of rows of a spreadsheet trying to get the digits to behave themselves. He’s a man after my own heart.
This accountant — call him Mr. Green — makes a good living helping people do their crypto-taxes.</description></item><item><title>TrueBlocks: First Quarter 2020 Update</title><link>/blog/trueblocks-first-quarter-2020-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 17:08:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/trueblocks-first-quarter-2020-update/</guid><description>This is short update on what we’ve been doing since receiving so many wonderful grants during the GitCoin CLR matching fandango. This money goes a long way. It allows one of us (Rush) to make a trip to EthDenver, where he will be judging some hacks. It has also paid for some much needed help developing the React frontend. If you donated (or even if you didn’t), and you’re in Denver this week, seek me out.</description></item><item><title>Simple Undeniable Facts</title><link>/blog/simple-undeniable-facts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 04:23:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/simple-undeniable-facts/</guid><description>One of the reasons I fell in love with blockchain tech way back in 2013 was because I felt that for the first time in history, engineers had created a system that could produced undeniable data. Undeniable access — yes, but more importantly, undeniably high-quality data. That was a paradigm shift.
While, technically, the data on a blockchain may be untrue, what is mathematically undeniable is that at least 51% of the participants have agreed that the data is consistent — maybe that’s as close as we can get to data being ‘true’.</description></item><item><title>A Time Ordered Index of Time Ordered Immutable Data</title><link>/blog/a-time-ordered-index-of-time-ordered-immutable-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 18:13:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/a-time-ordered-index-of-time-ordered-immutable-data/</guid><description>Did you ever notice that the only way to get the history of an Ethereum account is to visit a fully-centralized, database-driven, old-fashioned web-2.0 website?
Every time I use one of those sites (and I use them all the time), I think to myself: They’re watching me. They’ve attached my IP address to my address and in the future, they will wildly invading my privacy…but I need them…
Recently we demoed a fully decentralized blockchain explorer built on TrueBlocks.</description></item></channel></rss>