<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data model on</title><link>/data-model/</link><description>Recent content in Data model on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/data-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accounts</title><link>/data-model/accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/accounts/</guid><description>The primary tool of TrueBlocks is chifra export. This tool extracts, directly from the chain, entire transactional histories for one or more addresses and presents that information for use outside the blockchain. The results of this extraction is stored in a data structure called a Monitor.
Monitors collect together Appearances (blknum.tx_id pairs) along with additional information such as Reconciliations (18-decimal place accurate accounting for each asset transfer), Names (associations of human-readable names with addresses), and Abis which track the &amp;ldquo;meaning&amp;rdquo; of each transaction through its Functions and Parameters.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain data</title><link>/data-model/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/intro/</guid><description>TrueBlocks data On its own blockchain data is an unintelligable blob of binary bytes. But, we all know there is an amazing collection of deeply interesting information contained therein. Thousands of people are trading, voting, expressing their preferences, making markets for valueless items every minute.
What interests us about this data are answers to questions such as:
What exaclty is going on? Where is my money? Didn&amp;rsquo;t I have some of those tokens somewhere?</description></item><item><title>Unchained index</title><link>/data-model/the-index/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 09:35:59 -0300</pubDate><guid>/data-model/the-index/</guid><description>Benefits of unchaining the index We&amp;rsquo;ve written a lot about the Unchained Index elsewhere. We won&amp;rsquo;t belabour the point, however, we want to point out that the Unchained Index:
Allows blazingly fast access to any account anywhere on the chain Allows perfectly-private access to query blockchain data completely locally Naturally shards itself and distributes itself using IPFS and user behaviour Is published periodically to a smart contract and once published cannot be removed from public use Is reproducable directly from immutable data with a well-defined series of operations meaning its as immutable as the original blockchain data Compact Digs deeper into the blockchain than any other source allowing for instantaneous, 18-decimal-place accurate off-chain reconciliation of any account Blazingly fast Links to articles about TrueBlocks Here we present a number of articles we&amp;rsquo;ve written about TrueBlocks over the years.</description></item><item><title>Chain data</title><link>/data-model/chaindata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/chaindata/</guid><description>The following data structures describe the output of various TrueBlocks blockchain queries. These data structures basically mimic the data available directly from the RPC.
Each data structure is created by one or more tools which are detailed below.
Block chifra blocks returns top level data specified block. You can also include an array for the blocks&amp;rsquo; transactions.
The following commands produce and manage Blocks:
chifra blocks Blocks consist of the following fields:</description></item><item><title>Chain state</title><link>/data-model/chainstate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/chainstate/</guid><description>The data structures produced by tools in the Chain State category provide details on the balances (ERC20 or ETH) of an address against a particular token or block. Additionally, direct access to a smart contract&amp;rsquo;s state may be queries with the chirfa state tool. Data structures in that case are specific to the particular smart contract.
Each data structure is created by one or more tools which are detailed below.</description></item><item><title>Admin</title><link>/data-model/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/admin/</guid><description>The data models produced by the tools in the Admin category relate to scraping the chain, producing the Unchained Index, and querying the configuration of the system. Additional data related to sharing the indexes via IPFS and pinning the same are also produced by tools in this category.
Each data structure is created by one or more tools which are detailed below.
Status The chifra config tool reports on the state (and size) of the various TrueBlocks local binary caches.</description></item><item><title>Other</title><link>/data-model/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/data-model/other/</guid><description>The following commands provide useful miscellaneous tools:
chifra explore a quick way to open a blockchain explorer, ethslurp an older tool that lets you call data from EtherScan. (This has issues of centralization and data quality, see explanation in its section). Note: some of these tools, such as ethslurp, require an EtherScan key. Follow these instructions to add a key to your config.
Each data structure is created by one or more tools which are detailed below.</description></item></channel></rss>