<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monthly Token Balances</title><link>/blog/monthly-token-balances/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 02:00:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/monthly-token-balances/</guid><description> Read Creating Monthly Token Balances</description></item><item><title>Factories</title><link>/blog/factories/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 02:00:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/factories/</guid><description> Read About Contract Factories</description></item><item><title>Community Contributions</title><link>/blog/community-contributions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/community-contributions/</guid><description>From one of our community members. Thanks Leo!
For the fellow newbies, I took notes when starting this journey. I wrote a couple of posts I hope are helpful if you are setting up your own node with TrueBlocks.
Please note I focus on doing analytics. Storing and accessing the data are the most important factors for me. Thanks to everybody for the patience and helping me with all the issues!</description></item><item><title>Better Token Accounting</title><link>/blog/better-token-accounting/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/better-token-accounting/</guid><description>Eth accounting is identical Token accounting is improved in these ways:
Intra block token accounting Account for every Transfer event If a balance is incorrect, do one of three things: If the transaction contains a &amp;ldquo;large&amp;rdquo; input, and the event says something transferred, but the balances don&amp;rsquo;t change, lable probably-spam and add a field called removal of phony transfer in If the function is one of a very small number of common mint functions, assign to knownMint field If the function is one of a very small number of common burn methods, assign to a knownBurn field If the balance goes up - label the transation as implied-mint and add to a feild called impliedMint If the balance goes down - label the reconciliation as impied-burn and add to a field called impliedBurn Bugs fixed: In previous code, if a token transacted multple times in a single block the entire net transfer was assigned to the first transfer.</description></item><item><title>User contribution: Simple Blockchain Indexing with TrueBlocks</title><link>/blog/user-contribution-simple-blockchain-indexing-with-trueblocks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/user-contribution-simple-blockchain-indexing-with-trueblocks/</guid><description>&lt;p>An &lt;a href="https://dspyt.com/blockchain-data-indexer-with-trueblocks">article about TrueBlocks&lt;/a> and how our indexers work. Written by one of our community members.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FAQ</title><link>/blog/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:45:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/faq/</guid><description>A few of your more frequently asked questions
Are there ways to get ERC20 token balance for a given account address? Yes. There is. In fact, this is one of TrueBlocks&amp;rsquo; most important features. Simply do chifra export --statements &amp;lt;address(es)&amp;gt; or query the API serve with http://localhost:8080/export?addr=&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&amp;amp;statements.
Note that chifra export has many, many other options which produce similarly-informative data such as --logs, --appearances, --neighbors, --accounting, and so on. See the entire help file with chifra export --help.</description></item><item><title>forEveryChain</title><link>/blog/foreverychain/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 10:45:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/foreverychain/</guid><description>Have you ever had the desire to look at every trace of every transaction of every block on every blockchain? Yes? Well, pull up a chair and visit with us for a while.
It’s a Multi-Chain World I’m sure many of you are aware of the coming &amp;ldquo;multi-chain&amp;rdquo; universe of blockchains. You know the one. The one where all sorts of little baby communities of people are going to be doing all sorts of little baby community-like things.</description></item><item><title>Installing Erigon and TrueBlocks as Services on Ubuntu</title><link>/blog/installing-erigon-and-trueblocks-as-services-on-ubuntu/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/installing-erigon-and-trueblocks-as-services-on-ubuntu/</guid><description>One of our users (Magnus Hansson) has written an excellent article on how to install all three of Erigon, Erigon&amp;rsquo;s RPC, and TrueBlocks as serives on Ubuntu.
How to set up Erigon, Erigon’s RPC and TrueBlocks as services
Not only that &amp;ndash; the blog post is visually wonderful as well.
Thanks Magnus. Looking for some amazing data science from this quarter. Cheers.</description></item><item><title>Other articles published in 2021</title><link>/blog/other-articles-published-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/other-articles-published-in-2021/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s links to a few other articles we published in 2021 on Medium.
The Rent is Too Damn High The Rent is Too Damn High - Part II Adventures in Difficulty Bombing Calling Smart Contracts with chifra state --call Commanding the Line Compacting ERC20 Logs</description></item><item><title>Has EIP-1559 Fulfilled Its Objectives?</title><link>/blog/has-eip-1559-fulfilled-its-objectives/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 18:10:28 -0400</pubDate><guid>/blog/has-eip-1559-fulfilled-its-objectives/</guid><description>Pintail (twitter) wrote an amazing article on EIP-1559 and its effect on the Ethereum gas market. He used TrueBlocks to extract a bunch of his data. We get a nice mention at the end.
Thanks for the kind words, Pintail!</description></item></channel></rss>