<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About TrueBlocks</title><link>/docs/prologue/about-trueblocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 10:03:01 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/about-trueblocks/</guid><description>TrueBlocks provides a solution We think there are at least three fundamental problems with the current Ethereum ecosystem:
It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to run your own Ethereum node (not really, see below). Even if one runs a node, getting useful data is nearly impossible. All current solutions end up with a winner-take-all central database just like Google. We discuss each of these problems below.
Ethereum nodes are difficult to run Vitalik once called the Ethereum client software a &amp;ldquo;Big, Hairy node.</description></item><item><title>Design philosophy</title><link>/docs/prologue/design-philosophy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 10:03:01 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/design-philosophy/</guid><description>The three commandments Let users query this data without asking third-parties for permission.
If you can access blockchain data only through a third party (e.g. a cloud provider), is the data really decentralized?
Provide accurate access, to underived, consented-to, pure immutable data.
If the blockchain data is not accurate, what good is the blockchain?
Perform well on small machines
If an application requires web-scale computer infrastructure, does it really support decentralization?</description></item><item><title>Do I need a node?</title><link>/docs/prologue/do-i-need-a-node/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/do-i-need-a-node/</guid><description>And if you are running your own node, TrueBlocks works best with Erigon.
Why having a node is the best option Some benefits of TrueBlocks can be realized only when a user has their own node. Having a node lets users:
Limit queries to the node on their machine Use the node to build a local index Query data directly from the top of the chain Setting up a node is not as hard as many people think, but it does require two TBs of storage and some good hardware.</description></item><item><title>Multi chain</title><link>/docs/prologue/multi-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 10:03:01 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/multi-chain/</guid><description>Accessing multiple chains As of version 0.25.0-alpha, TrueBlocks supports accessing data from any EVM-based blockchain that supports the requisite RPC endpoints. This includes most blockchains we know of.
In order to use this new feature, you have to do almost nothing. All you have to do is add --chain &amp;lt;chainname&amp;gt; to any chifra command (except one or two as detailed below).
For example:
Command Notes chifra blocks 12 Default chain is mainnet chifra blocks 12 &amp;ndash;chain mainnet Same as default chifra blocks 12 &amp;ndash;chain gnosis Block 12 from gnosis chain How can this possibly work?</description></item></channel></rss>