<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chifra Command Line on</title><link>/chifra/</link><description>Recent content in Chifra Command Line on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/chifra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accounts</title><link>/chifra/accounts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/accounts/</guid><description>The Accounts group of commands is at the heart of TrueBlocks. They allow you to produce and analyze transactional histories for one or more Ethereum addresses.
You may also name addresses; grab the ABI file for a given address; add, delete, and remove monitors, and, most importantly, export transactional histories in various formats, This includes re-directing output to remote or local databases.
To the right is a list of commands in this group.</description></item><item><title>Using chifra</title><link>/chifra/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/introduction/</guid><description>Similar to git, TrueBlocks has an overarching command called chifra that gives you access to all of the other subcommands.
Type:
chifra You will see a long list of commands similar to this
Usage: chifra command Purpose: Access to all TrueBlocks tools (chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help for more). Where: Accounts: list list every appearance of an address anywhere on the chain export export full detail of transactions for one or more addresses monitors add, remove, clean, and list address monitors names query addresses or names of well known accounts abis fetches the ABI for a smart contract Chain Data: blocks retrieve one or more blocks from the chain or local cache transactions retrieve one or more transactions from the chain or local cache receipts retrieve receipts for the given transaction(s) logs retrieve logs for the given transaction(s) traces retrieve traces for the given transaction(s) when find block(s) based on date, blockNum, timestamp, or 'special' Chain State: state retrieve account balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) tokens retrieve token balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) Admin: config report on and edit the configuration of the TrueBlocks system daemon initalize and control long-running processes such as the API and the scrapers scrape scan the chain and update the TrueBlocks index of appearances chunks manage, investigate, and display the Unchained Index init initialize the TrueBlocks system by downloading from IPFS Other: explore open a local or remote explorer for one or more addresses, blocks, or transactions slurp fetch data from EtherScan for any address You may get more help on any command by typing chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help.</description></item><item><title>Tutorials</title><link>/chifra/using/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/using/</guid><description>A few more examples in more detail.
Getting help Every chifra sub-command comes with an associated help page. To get help for chifra itself, simply type
chifra A long list of commands should show. (If you have trouble, see the Installation page.)
To get help for a specific command, type
chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help To get more detailed help, type
chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help --verbose 2 Getting system status The chifra command gives you access to all of TrueBlocks&amp;rsquo; functionality.</description></item><item><title>Chain data</title><link>/chifra/chaindata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/chaindata/</guid><description>The Chain Data group of tools extract raw blockchain data directly from the node. You may extract block data, transactional data, receipts, logs, traces, and other information. Each tool has it own set of options, allowing you to get exactly the data you need.
To the right is a list of commands in this group. Click on a command to see its full documentation.
chifra blocks The chifra blocks tool retrieves block data from your Ethereum node or, if previously cached, from the TrueBlocks cache.</description></item><item><title>Chain state</title><link>/chifra/chainstate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/chainstate/</guid><description>The two tools in this group deal with the Chain State. As chain state data concerns balances and byte code. it is distinct from Chain Data, which concerns things like blocks, transactions, or traces.
chifra state allows you to query the ETH account balance for an address, the byte code of a smart contract (if available), the nonce, and other information about an address. The second tool, chifra tokens, deals with ERC20 and ERC721 token balances and related data.</description></item><item><title>Admin</title><link>/chifra/admin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/admin/</guid><description>The Admin gourp of commands allows you to query the status of the TrueBlocks system and manage various apects including the Unchained Index. You may query the status; query for information about TrueBlocks caches; control the creation, sharing, and pinning of the Unchained Index; and even serve the data through an API.
See the API documentation for all information about using the API.
To the right is a list of commands in this group.</description></item><item><title>Other</title><link>/chifra/other/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/other/</guid><description>The commands in the Other group provide useful miscellaneous features.
chifra explore provides a quick way to open the configured blockchain explorer, ethslurp (an older tool) allows you call extract data from EtherScan. To the right is a list of commands in this group. Click on a command to see its full documentation.
Note: Some of these tools, such as ethslurp, require an API key. Follow these instructions to add a key to your config.</description></item><item><title>Configurations</title><link>/chifra/configs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/chifra/configs/</guid><description>Many of the chifra commands allow you to customize their behaviour through configuration files and/or environment variables. These options are documented here.
Environment variables Each command-line option may be overridden by exporting an environment variable in your shell prior to running a chifra command.
The name of those environment variables is as follows:
The environment variable is ALL_UPPER_CASE The environment variable name preserves underbars in the item_name The name of the variable starts with the group the item belongs to For example: GROUP_ITEM_NAME.</description></item></channel></rss>