<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on</title><link>/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install core</title><link>/docs/install/install-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/install/install-core/</guid><description>These instructions assume you can navigate the command line and edit configuration files. If you need help with a particular step, see the installation&amp;rsquo;s troubleshooting section.
Installation Open a terminal window.
Type go version. If Go is not installed or your version is less than 1.18.0, install the latest version of Go
Install or upgrade the build dependancies: git, cmake, ninja, curl, python, clang-format, jq
Install dependencies Clone the repo and compile the executable:</description></item><item><title>Unchained Index</title><link>/docs/install/build-unchained-index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:19:51 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/install/build-unchained-index/</guid><description>If you want&amp;hellip; and you don&amp;rsquo;t mind&amp;hellip; then use&amp;hellip; to minimize the size of the data stored locally and
you want to get started faster&amp;hellip; slower first-time queries on new addresses, an index
that&amp;rsquo;s slightly behind the head of the chain, an index
created by someone else&amp;hellip; chifra init to maximize the speed of first-time queries for
new addresses&amp;hellip; longer initial setup time, ~70 GB of local storage, an</description></item><item><title>Install explorer</title><link>/docs/install/install-explorer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 08:01:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/install/install-explorer/</guid><description>First, make sure that you have the chifra-core backend up and running, then run the application from a clone of the explorer repo.
Before you begin ☑ Set up the trueblocks backend using the chifra installation instructions
☑ In a terminal window, run the command chifra serve
Install Keep the chifra serve process running.
Then, in a new terminal, run these commands:
git clone git@github.com:TrueBlocks/trueblocks-explorer.git cd trueblocks-explorer cp .env.example .env yarn yarn develop Open your browser, and access the app from localhost:1234.</description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting</title><link>/docs/install/install-troubleshooting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/install/install-troubleshooting/</guid><description>This section lists solutions to problems some users have run into with the installation. If you continue to have trouble, create an issue, or ask us on discord.
Dependencies Installing go How do I check my Go version? Run this command
go version TrueBlocks needs version 1.16.x or later. If you to install or update Go, see here.
Installing build tools How do I install the build packages for my system?</description></item></channel></rss>